## ROBBIE KIRKBRIDE | SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

London, UK | +447788930837 | robbie.w.m.kirkbride@gmail.com <u>GitHub</u> | <u>Website</u> | <u>Blog</u> | <u>LinkedIn</u>

## **PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY**

As a Software Developer and former Civil Engineer for 5 years, I'm driven by a passion for tech, continuous learning, and making positive impacts. I'm a proactive, language-agnostic coder with a knack for rapidly acquiring new skills and am looking to bring my professionalism to a new role.

	CORE COMPETENCIES
Languages	TypeScript, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Ruby, Python
Languages	
Libraries/frameworks	React, Node.JS, Express.JS, Tailwind, Jest, Cypress, RSpec, Sinatra
Architecture	MCV, Microservices, REST, SPA
Tools	MongoDB, PostgresSQL, GitHub, JWT, Postman, Trello
	EXPERIENCE

Makers Academy - October 2022 to February 2023

Ecoliday - MongoDB, Express.js, React, Node.js, JWT, Tailwind, Jest, Cypress (GitHuB)

- Eco-conscious travel planner created during my two week Makers final project in a five person Agile team with sprints, stand-ups, retros and daily pair programming.
- Built with the MERN stack using GitHub for Version Control. I used my pragmatic mindset to tailor the MVP and tickets to ensure delivery of a consistently usable product.
- Created a REST API that called three third party APIs (climatiq, geoapify, google maps), with a
  total of eight calls made per search.

Frontleft - TypeScript, MongoDB, Express.js, React, Node.js, JWT, CSS, Jest, Cypress (GitHub)

- A festival planner app developed with TypeScript, featuring integrated CI/CD pipelines.
- Built from the ground up with the MERN stack, implementing JWT authentication, Bcrypt password encryption, Sendgrid email notifications and file uploads with Multer/Sharp.

## **COWI UK** - Engineering Consultant - January 2018 to October 2022

- Proven Project Manager, adept at stakeholder engagement, client expectation management, program oversight, and quality assurance, continually adhering to ISO standards.
- Developed in-house design software tools in VBA, using Git for version control.
- Used Python to analyse Point Cloud Survey datasets of structures to offer savings to clients.
- Processed topographical data using MATLAB to streamline design calculations.
- Co-founded an interoffice network that organised conferences, technical and social events.
- Delivered the design of a 300m tall mast with 33% less CO2e than the initial proposal, with additional cost and programme savings, despite working under intense time pressure.
- Led development of FEA models and fatigue analysis of the Mumbai Trans Harbour Link.

## **EDUCATION**

Makers Academy - Coding Bootcamp - October 2022 to February 2023

- Focus on language-agnostic development by building strong self-directed study skills and best practices such as test-driven development, version control and agile methodologies.
- Excelled due to my strong analytical thinking and systematic approach, both in planning and production, establishing watertight TDD processes and debugging techniques.
- Communicated complex content methodically and concisely whilst pairing and working in Agile teams, a skill fostered as a Project Manager at COWI.
- Signed up to the mentoring scheme, as I carried forward my trait of leadership from COWI.

University of Bristol - Civil Engineering, MEng (First Class) - 2013 to 2017

Marlborough College - A level: Maths (A\*), Further Maths (A), French (A), Physics (B)